PIYUSH KALYANI

Full-Stack / Backend Developer

7849955225 | piyush.kalyani7@gmail.com | Portfolio-site | LInkedin | Github

SUMMARY:

Full-stack developer **experienced in: React, Node.js, and Django** Skilled in system design & database design **SKILLS**: **Python, Sql, Javascript, Typescript, Django, Express.js, Node.js, React, Git, Docker, GraphQl, REST API, FastAPI, AWS, HTML, CSS**

ABOUT: Full-stack developer with 2+years of experience, blending analytical thinking with creative problem-solving. My background spans coding, family business management, and psychology studies. This diverse experience enhances my ability to contribute effectively in collaborative tech environments

WORK EXPERIENCE (2y+):

<u>Infollion Research Services, Gurugram | Full Stack Developer (On-site)</u>

April 2024 - Present

- Leveraged React with Material-UI for frontend and Node.js with Sequelize for backend in development
- Integrated Zoom Meeting SDK for call hosting and masking user identities and reducing setup time by over 90%.
- Implemented Amazon SES alongside SendGrid, reducing email bounce rates for Yahoo by approximately 70%, and configured S3 buckets for storage and integration
- Contributed to technical design discussions and led interviews for full-stack and backend developer roles
- Enhanced internal dashboard by developing new features and optimizing existing ones, implementing filtering, data highlighting for improved tracking, implementing query optimization, and streamlined backend processes

<u>Bizmorphic, Pune | Full Stack Developer (Remote, Freelance)</u>

November 2023 - March 2024

- Contributed to client projects and internal product development using React, Node.js, and Appwrite,
- designed a recommendation algorithm and participated in product strategy discussions

<u>Dataphi, Bangalore | Full Stack Developer Intern (Remote)</u>

January 2023 - September 2023

- Contributed to **multiple projects** including a document management site, school internship platform, and admin dashboard, gig platform (led frontend).
- Created **GraphQL APIs** with **Django and Node.js**, assisted with AWS S3 integration, and React-Firebase notification system.
- Developed frontend using React, Formik, Yup, Zustand, and GraphQL with Apollo, translating Figma designs into interfaces

<u>EQ Capital, Delhi | Full Stack Developer Intern (Remote, Part-time)</u>

July 2022 - December 2022

Assisted in MVP development, converting Figma designs to React components and creating Django APIs

PROJECTS:

VibeVault & VibeMatch: Live link | github

- A personal creation: It's a **2in1 app.** This **MERN** stack application allows users to rate and follow a wide range of media, and maintain a list, **similar to AniList or IMDb**, but for everything including books, anime, shows & movies.
- It also features VibeMatch, which uses a FastAPI backend to match users based on their media preferences it's like Tinder,
 but the matchmaking is based on your media list

Django-React E-commerce Platform: Live link | github

Built an ecommerce platform using Django, React with, JWT authentication, Redux, and had admin capabilities

Al Posture Detection for Yoga (R&D project): github

- Yoga posture detection using **Python, OpenCV**, Scikit-learn, Mediapipe, Streamlit, **Pandas**,, and WebRTC.
- Approved research paper for publication.

Other projects: github

Next.js portfolio, Flutter crud notes app, Data analytics assignments, python script to change folder names in bulk, MERN chat appusing socket.io/webSocket

Education:

NIIT University:

August 2019 - August 2023

M.sc CS | AI specialization Cloud & Blockchain Elective